Guide to the Merle Hoffman Papers, circa 1944-2012 and undated, bulk 1961-2000 RL.00557
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- On the Issues Series, 1980-2000 and undated, bulk 1990s, 27 boxes
  - Correspondence Subseries, 1987-2000 and undated
    - Handel, Carolyn (advertising sales), 1990-1991 (Box OTI3)
    - Handel, Carolyn (advertising sales and circulation), 1995-1996 (Box OTI3)
    - Hoffman, Merle, 1989, 1991-1992, 1995-1996, 6 folders (Box OTI3)
    - Hoffman, Merle, 1997-1998, 1 of 2 folders (Box OTI3)
    - Hoffman, Merle, 1997-1998, 2 of 2 folders (Box OTI4)
    - Hoffman, Merle, correspondence with staff, 1996-1997 (Box OTI4)
    - Marketing, 1996-1997 (Box OTI4)
    - Memos, 1997 (Box OTI4)
    - Notice of suspension to Post Office, 1999 July 1 (Box OTI4)
    - Reader discussion group and regional representative volunteers, 1997 (Box OTI4)
    - Readers, 1991 and 1996-1998 (Box OTI4)
    - Reprint requests, 1987-1996, 6 folders (Box OTI4)
    - Reprint requests, 1997-1999, 3 folders (Box OTI5)
    - Sokol, Lori (advertising sales), 1997-1998 (Box OTI5)
    - Subscriber form letters, 1995-1996 and undated (Box OTI5)
    - Subscriptions, 1998 (Box OTI5)
    - Subscriptions - complaints, 1993, 1996-1997, 2 folders (Box OTI5)
    - Subscriptions - complaints about billing errors, 1998 (Box OTI5)
    - Writers' guides and periodicals indexes, 1992-1997 (Box OTI5)
    - Yager, Sara (web site), 1995-1998 (Box OTI5)
  - Article Files Subseries, 1980-1998 and undated, bulk 1997-1998
    Consists primarily of printouts of electronic draft versions of On the Issues articles. Electronic draft versions of articles for earlier issues can be found in the Electronic Format Subseries. Articles are arranged alphabetically by author last name.
    - Atkins, Dawn and Mary, Fat Activism - pamphlets, 1995 (Box OTI5)
    - Aung San Suu Kyi interview, 1998 (Box OTI5)
    - Aylon, Helene (photographer), correspondence, 1996-1997 (Box OTI5)
    - Bader, Eleanor, review of Who's Afraid of Feminism?, circa 1997 (Box OTI5)
    - Baird, Bill, interview and related materials, 1980-1992 (Box OTI6)
    - Baraheni, Reza, "Exile, Language and Imagination," 1998 (Box OTI6)
    - Benet, Siobhan, essay on Claire Bloom, 1996 (Box OTI6)
    - Bennett, Maria, "When They Took the Bed Away," 1997 (Box OTI6)
    - Brockway, Michelle, "Saving the World," 1998 (Box OTI6)
    - Bruce, Tammy and Julianne Malveaux dialogue, 1996 (Box OTI6)
    - Chesler, Phyllis
      - "A Meditation on the Sea," 1998 (Box OTI6)
      - Review of Shulamith Firestone's Airless Spaces, 1998 (Box OTI6)
      - "What Is Justice for a Rape Victim?," 1995-1996 (Box OTI6)
      - "Zen and the Art of Motherhood," 1998 (Box OTI6)
    - Cole, Ellen, review of Joanna Russ' What Are We Fighting For?, 1998 (Box OTI6)
    - Coventry, Martha, "Mutilating Our Children," 1998 (Box OTI6)
    - Delaney, Anngel, "Sports Endurance," 1998 (Box OTI6)
    - Derricotte, Toi, The Black Notebooks excerpt, 1998 and undated (Box OTI7)
    - Dworkin, Andrea, article - editorial correspondence, 1995 June 2 (Box OTI7)
    - Finkelstein, Katherine Eban, "Title T/K," 1997 (Box OTI7)
    - Gage, Carolyn, "Why Annie Got Her Gun," copyright and reprint problems, 1996-1997 (Box OTI7)
    - Garcia, Maria, "Artists of the Dreamtime," 1997 (Box OTI7)
    - Geller, Jaclyn
      - "OTI Goes to a Wedding," 1997 (Box OTI7)
      - Review of Freud's Paranoid Quest, 1998 (Box OTI7)
    - Goodwin, Jan
      - "Afghanistan's Taliban," 1993 (Box OTI7)
      - "Trafficking in Women and Girls," 1998 (Box OTI7)
    - Green, Westry, "Mother's Day: Notes on Being a Long-Distance Lesbian Mom," 1998 (Box OTI7)
    - Greenberg, Mary Lou
      - "America's Political Prisoners," 1998 (Box OTI7)
      - "Anti-Abortion Suffragists," 1998 (Box OTI7)
      - "The Fire This Time: When 'Pro-Life' Means Death," 1998 (Box OTI7)
    - Gurwitt, Andrea, "Losing Feminist Daughters to Orthodoxy," 1996 (Box OTI7)
    - Haskell, Molly, "Fountain of Youth: For Men Only," 1998 (Box OTI7)
    - Haskell, Molly, "Women at Turning Points," 1998 (Box OTI8)
    - Hassibi, Mahin
      - "Designing Sex, Regulating Sexuality," 1998 (Box OTI8)
      - Review of Charlene Spretnak, The Resurgence of the Real, 1998 (Box OTI8)
    - Hilty, Joan, cartoon, 1998 (Box OTI8)
    - Hoffman, Merle
      - Correspondence and materials for editorials, 1985 and undated (Box OTI8)
      - Materials for editorials, 1990 and undated, 2 folders (Box OTI8)
      - Interview with Carol Bower, Cape Town Rape Crisis, 1997 (Box OTI8)
      - Interview with Carol Bower, fact-checking materials, 1997, 3 folders (Box OTI8)
    - Hood, Jenifer Kay, "The Art of Judy Schaurien," 1997 (Box OTI8)
    - "Human Rights - A World Report" - introduction, 1998 (Box OTI8)
    - Hunt, Swanee, "A Personal View of Women and Public Policy," 1998 (Box OTI8)
    - Innaurato, Albert, "Music? They Even Blamed Women for Chocolate," 1998, 1 of 2 folders (Box OTI8)
    - Innaurato, Albert, "Music? They Even Blamed Women for Chocolate," 1998, 2 of 2 folders (Box OTI9)
    - Ireland, Patricia (National Organization for Women), interview, 1998 (Box OTI9)
    - Kean, Leslie, interview with Alan Clements on Aung San Suu Kyi, 1997 (Box OTI9)
    - Kleinman, Sherryl, "The Nose Job," 1998 (Box OTI9)
    - Lader, Lawrence, "Leading Las Vegas," 1997 (Box OTI9)
    - Lynch, Amy, "Secrets," 1998 (Box OTI9)
    - Martin, Amy, "Fidelistas and Feministas," 1998 (Box OTI9)
    - McNair, Marcia, "The Black Matriarchy - Revisited," 1998 (Box OTI9)
    - Melich, Tanya, "Turnout or Turnoff in 1998," 1998 (Box OTI9)
    - Menon, Kavita, "Layli Miller Bashir," 1998 (Box OTI9)
    - Millard, Elizabeth, review of Mary Daly, Realizing the Archaic Future, 1998 (Box OTI9)
    - Nix, Jennifer, review of A New Kind of Party Animal, 1998 (Box OTI9)
    - Pettifer, Ann, "Contraception War," 1998 (Box OTI9)
    - Peyser, Andrea, "Meditations on Motherhood," 1998 (Box OTI9)
    - Piercy, Marge, "Thou shalt not complain about anything I might have to fix," poem, 1997 (Box OTI9)
    - Rapping, Elayne, "The Trap of the Essentialist 'Good Girl,' " circa 1996 (Box OTI9)
    - Millett, Kate
      - "Meditations on Aging and Being Unemployable," 1998 (Box OTI9)
      - Readers' correspondence, 1998 (Box OTI9)
    - Readers' letters - editing, Fall 1998 (Box OTI9)
    - Readers' letters for Fall 1998 issue, 1998 (Box OTI9)
    - Rosenberg, Susan, interview and correspondence, 1989-1998 (Box OTI10)
    - Rudo, Marcy, "Lluisa Vidal, Daughter of Modernism," 1998 (Box OTI10)
    - Russell, Diana, "The People vs. Larry Flynt," 1997 and undated (Box OTI10)
    - Seitz, Charmaine, "Palestinian Women and Their Dream Deferred," 1997 (Box OTI10)
    - Snortland, Ellen, "Bitch Bitch Bitch," 1995 (Box OTI10)
    - Stabin, Tova, midwifery article, 1998 (Box OTI10)
    - Stamen, Jayne, correspondence, 1994 (Box OTI10)
    - Stasio, Marilyn
      - "Emma Thompson," 1998 (Box OTI10)
      - "Gender, Sex and Politics in Shakespeare," 1998 (Box OTI10)
      - "Sightlines," 1998 (Box OTI10)
    - Stoller, Debbie, "Brave New Girls," 1998 (Box OTI10)
    - Szalavitz, Maia, "How the War on Drugs Fails Women," 1998 (Box OTI10)
    - Talking Feminist column, typescripts, 1997 (Box OTI10)
    - Thompson, Karen, interview, 1986 (Box OTI10)
    - Tierney, Jennifer, "A Place at the Table," 1998 (Box OTI10)
    - Tierney, Jennifer, interview with Charlotte Bunch, 1998 (Box OTI11)
    - Tucker, Dolores and Jewell Jackson McCabe dialogue, 1995 (Box OTI11)
    - Wagner, Sally Roesch, "The Iroquois Influence on Feminism," 1996 (Box OTI11)
    - Ward, Joy, "The Judge Who Got Off," 1996 (Box OTI11)
    - Wiesel, Elie, interview, 1990-1991 (Box OTI11)
    - Wenzel, Lynn, "An Ecofeminist Reclamation Project" and background materials, 1990-1997 and undated, 2 folders (Box OTI11)
    - Yahn, Mimi, "View to a Kill," 1998 (Box OTI11)
  - Editorial Files Subseries, 1986-1999 and undated
    Includes a variety of material documenting the activities of the editorial staff and the magazine's contributors. Contents include contributors' contracts and correspondence, files on annual staff retreats, subject files on topics of interest to Editor-at-Large Phyllis Chesler, and other story idea files. Arranged alphabetically.
    - Alternative media questionnaire and conferences, 1995-1996 (Box OTI11)
    - Authors' queries, 1998 (Box OTI11)
    - Authors' queries and manuscripts, 1996-1998 (Box OTI11)
    - Authors' queries - rejected, 1997 (Box OTI11)
    - Book reviews - publisher contact information for book requests, 1996-1998 and undated (Box OTI12)
    - Book reviews - review copies requested, 1996-1997 and undated (Box OTI12)
    - Book reviews - review copies requested for Phyllis Chesler, 1996-1997 (Box OTI12)
    - Bosnia women's magazine, proposal to assist, 1996 (Box OTI12)
    - Call for contributions - Women's Studies mailing, 1994 Mar. (Box OTI12)
    - Contributor contracts - revised, 1995 (Box OTI12)
    - Contributor contracts, 1994-1996, and 1998, 2 folders (Box OTI12)
    - Contributor payments (Winter 1999 issue), 1999 (Box OTI12)
    - Contributor payments and contracts, 1994-1998, 1-6 of 12 folders (Box OTI12)
    - Contributor payments and contracts, 1994-1998, 7-12 of 12 folders (Box OTI13)
    - Contributor payments - form letter, 1998 (Box OTI13)
    - Contributors' correspondence and contracts, 1994-1998, 5 folders (Box OTI13)
    - Contributors - Reprint permission agreements, 1996-1997 (Box OTI13)
    - Crosby, Suzanne Hall (Skinner), court records and correspondence, 1986-1990 and undated, 2 folders (Box OTI13)
    - Editorial prospectus, John Stoltenberg, 1995 July 1 (Box OTI14)
    - Fairness and Accuracy in Reporting (FAIR) media list, 1991 (Box OTI14)
    - Fifth Annual Origins/BSN Conference, 1990 (Box OTI14)
    - Gordon, Beate Sirota, memoir - press kit for review, 1997-1998 (Box OTI14)
    - Hoffman, Merle, press pass and business cards, undated (Box OTI14)
    - Merge feminist zine - sample issues, 1998 (Box OTI14)
    - Morgan, Elizabeth - custody case, 1989 (Box OTI14)
    - Political cartoons submitted, 1991-1993 (Box OTI14)
    - Prostitution, 1988-1993 (Box OTI14)
    - Readership survey, 1993, 1996 Sept., 3 folders (Box OTI14)
    - Recovered memory materials, 1997 (Box OTI14)
    - Retreat planning and materials, 1993-1994, 3 folders (Box OTI14)
    - Retreat planning and materials, 1996 Oct., 1 of 2 folders (Box OTI14)
    - Retreat planning and materials, 1996 Oct., 2 of 2 folders (Box OTI15)
    - Retreat planning and materials, 1998 Feb. (Box OTI15)
    - Riben, Marsha, adoption and birthparents' rights, 1988-1989 and undated (Box OTI15)
    - "Short Takes" feature ideas, 1998 Apr. (Box OTI15)
    - Story ideas, 1995-1998, 3 folders (Box OTI15)
    - Story ideas and assignments, 1998 (Box OTI15)
    - Story ideas and marketing survey, 1998-1999 (Box OTI15)
    - Story ideas for Winter 1999, 1997-1998 and undated (Box OTI15)
    - Story kill fees, 1996 (Box OTI15)
    - Thomas, Clarence, Anita Hill, and Supreme Court - clippings and mailings, 1991-1992 (Box OTI15)
    - Village Voice clipping on Roe v. Wade, 1998 Jan. 27 (Box OTI15)
    - Women's News and Narratives newsletter, Autumn 1996 (Box OTI15)
    - Writer's guidelines, 1998 and undated (Box OTI15)
  - Marketing Subseries, 1986-1998 and undated
    Arranged into three further divisions: Direct Mail Marketing, Issue Publicity, and General Marketing Files. The Direct Mail Subseries documents the magazine's mass mailings to potential subscribers. The Issue Publicity Subseries consists of press releases and other publicity for specific articles or issues of the magazine. Arranged alphabetically within each group.
    - Direct Mail Marketing, 1992-1998 and undated
      - Braren, Warren, 1992 (Box OTI15)
      - Fine Print Distributors joint promotion, 1996-1997 (Box OTI15)
      - Gift acknowledgment card prices, 1998 (Box OTI15)
      - Keating, Anne, 1994-1996, 2 folders (Box OTI15)
      - List exchanges, 1992-1994 (Box OTI15)
      - List rental, 1990-1995, 1-2 of 3 folders (Box OTI15)
      - List rental, 1990-1995, 3 of 3 folders (Box OTI16)
      - List rental selections, 1998 Mar. (Box OTI16)
      - List statistics, 1992-1995 (Box OTI16)
      - RMI Direct Marketing, 1993 (Box OTI16)
      - Sample issue offers
        - (1992 June), 1992 and undated (Box OTI16)
        - (1992 Sept.), 1992 (Box OTI16)
        - (1992 Dec.) - list rental, 1992-1993 (Box OTI16)
        - (1993 Sept.), 1993 (Box OTI16)
        - (1994 Sept.), 1994 and undated (Box OTI16)
        - (1994 Sept.) - list rental selections, 1994 (Box OTI16)
        - (1994 Sept.) - response analysis, 1994 and undated (Box OTI16)
        - (1995 Jan.), 1994-1995 (Box OTI16)
        - (1996 Dec.) and response statistics, 1996-1997 (Box OTI16)
      - Tyson Associates, 1996-1998, 1-2 of 4 folders (Box OTI16)
      - Tyson Associates, 1996-1998, 3-4 of 4 folders (Box OTI17)
      - Women's Q and A mailing, 1997 (Box OTI17)
    - Issue Publicity, 1990-1998
      - "Bitch" story, 1995 Jan. 5 (Box OTI17)
      - Chesler, Phyllis, "Claiming Sacred Ground," 1996 (Box OTI17)
      - Clinic terrorism story, 1995 Jan. 5 (Box OTI17)
      - Female genital mutilation story, 1998 May 15 (Box OTI17)
      - Feminist heroes editorial, 1996 Nov. (Box OTI17)
      - Howard Rubenstein Associates, 1990 (Box OTI17)
      - Iranian women story and Fall 1994 issue, 1994, 2 folders (Box OTI17)
      - "Phallic Drift" story, 1994 Apr. 11 (Box OTI17)
      - Press releases, 1994-1995 (Box OTI17)
      - "Promise Keepers" story, 1994-1995 (Box OTI17)
      - Richard Cohen Associates, 1996 (Box OTI17)
      - The Rosen Group, press releases and media coverage, 1995-1997 (Box OTI17)
      - Wiesel, Elie, interview, 1991 (Box OTI17)
      - Winter 1995 issue, 1994 Dec. 2 (Box OTI17)
    - General Marketing Files, 1986-1998 and undated
      - Advertisement design, 1994 and undated (Box OTI17)
      - Advertisements for On the Issues, 1995-1998 and undated (Box OTI17)
      - Amnesty International mailing, 1996 (Box OTI17)
      - Barcelona Feminist Book Fair, 1990, 3 folders (Box OTI18)
      - Camera-ready advertisements for On the Issues, 1998 Feb. 4 (Box OTI18)
      - Circulation analysis and Dec. 1996 direct mail analysis, 1996 (Box OTI18)
      - Circulation Management magazine, 1997 Nov. (Box OTI18)
      - Circulation strategies and consultants, 1995 and n.d (Box OTI18)
      - College Store Executive magazine advertising, 1998 (Box OTI18)
      - Community Action Network media award nomination, 1994 (Box OTI18)
      - EBSCO's Librarians' Handbook advertising, 1998 (Box OTI18)
      - Electronic Newsstand advertising, 1995 (Box OTI18)
      - Feminist bookstores, 1994 and undated (Box OTI18)
      - Flyers for distributors, undated (Box OTI18)
      - The Folio:Show seminars, notes on increasing circulation, 1994 (Box OTI18)
      - Invitation mailing lists, 1997-1998 (Box OTI18)
      - Library distribution organizations, 1996 (Box OTI18)
      - Magazine catalog advertising, 1998 (Box OTI18)
      - Marketing proposal, 1996 Nov. 7 (Box OTI18)
      - National Organization for Women (NOW) conference exhibit, 1997 (Box OTI18)
      - NOW conference programs with On the Issues advertising, 1988-1996 (Box OTI18)
      - NOW-News advertisement, 1998 (Box OTI18)
      - NOW Women of Color Summit advertising, 1998 (Box OTI18)
      - On the Issues exhibit - banner and button design, 1996 (Box OTI18)
      - On the Issues flyer for Central Books distributors, 1997 (Box OTI18)
      - Pamphlets and forms, 1998 (Box OTI18)
      - Press reviews of On the Issues, 1986-1998 (Box OTI19)
      - Publicity, The Rosen Group, 1995-1996 (Box OTI19)
      - Renewal and subscription reminder form letters, 1998 and undated (Box OTI19)
      - Renewal reminder and payment reminder design, 1998 and undated (Box OTI19)
      - Renewal reminder envelope design, 1994, 1998 and undated, 2 folders (Box OTI19)
      - Renewal reminder design, 1994-1995 (Box OTI19)
      - Retail Promotion Programs guide, Eastern News Distributors, 1996 (Box OTI19)
      - Takeover of New Directions for Women subscriber list, 1993-1995 (Box OTI19)
      - Teen Voices magazine, sample issue and proposed ad trade, 1995 (Box OTI19)
      - Utne Reader sales leads, 1997 (Box OTI19)
      - WBAI radio publicity - new subscribers, 1990 (Box OTI19)
      - Web site utilization statistics, 1995-1997, 2 folders (Box OTI19)
      - Women's Studies mailing, 1998 (Box OTI19)
  - Production and Distribution Subseries, 1983-1999 and undated
    Folders contain production schedules, art director's files, and other materials related to the layout and final editing of each issue. Distribution reports provide evidence of where the magazine was marketed on the newsstands and how large a circulation the magazine attained in these venues. The subseries is divided into two sections, the first organized chronologically by magazine issue and the second alphabetically by subject. See the Oversize Material for additional layout materials and distribution reports.
    - Production by Issue, 1983-1998 and undated
      - 1983 June-July issue, layout, 1983 (Box OTI19)
      - 1995 Winter issue
        - Story list, 1994 Oct. 18 (Box OTI19)
        - Advertising statistics for Post Office, 1994 Nov. (Box OTI19)
        - Press run and distribution, 1994 Nov. (Box OTI19)
      - 1995 Spring issue, press run and distribution, 1995 Jan.-May and undated (Box OTI19)
      - 1995 Summer issue, production schedule, 1995 Mar. 2 (Box OTI19)
      - 1997 Spring issue, production schedule meeting, 1996 (Box OTI19)
      - 1997 Summer issue, Hoffman's copy for final edits, 1997 (Box OTI19)
      - 1998 Winter issue, story update, 1998 (Box OTI20)
      - 1998 Spring issue, artwork and layout planning, 1997-1998, 2 folders (Box OTI20)
      - 1998 Summer issue
        - Bella Abzug dedication, 1998 (Box OTI20)
        - Hoffman's copy for final edits, 1998 (Box OTI20)
        - Story list and final edits, 1998 (Box OTI20)
      - 1998 Fall issue
        - Story update, 1998 May (Box OTI20)
        - Copy for final edits, 1998 (Box OTI20)
        - Layout and editing, 1998 (Box OTI20)
      - 1999 Winter issue, cover art, circa 1998 (Box OTI20)
    - Production by Subject, 1987-1999 and undated
      - Advertisements, 1995-1998 and undated, 4 folders (Box OTI20)
      - Artwork, circa 1991-1998 and undated (Box OTI20)
      - Artwork and advertisements, 1992-1998 and undated, 4 folders (Box OTI20)
      - Artwork planning and printing costs, 1997, 2 folders (Box OTI20)
      - Contracts with distributors, 1987-1997 (Box OTI20)
      - Eve's Garden advertising, 1996 (Box OTI20)
      - Impact Visuals (photo library), 1990-1992 (Box OTI20)
      - Issue planning, 1995, 1998, 2 folders (Box OTI21)
      - Issue planning and production schedule, 1997 and undated (Box OTI21)
      - Joy Makon Design, artwork, 1996 (Box OTI21)
      - Postal invoices, 1997-1998 (Box OTI21)
      - Press runs and distribution, 1988-1998 and undated, 4 folders (Box OTI21)
      - Printing and postal invoices, 1997-1998 (Box OTI21)
      - Production process and production assistant responsibilities, notes, 1988, 1996 and undated (Box OTI21)
      - Production schedules, 1997-1998 (Box OTI21)
      - Sales and returns reports for small distributors, 1996-1998, 2 folders (Box OTI21)
      - Sales reports, Eastern News Distributors, 1996-1999, 1-2 of 3 folders (Box OTI21)
      - Sales reports, Eastern News Distributors, 1996-1999, 3 of 3 folders (Box OTI22)
      - Public service announcements, 1998 (Box OTI22)
      - University of Oklahoma Press advertisement, 1998 (Box OTI22)
  - Staff Files Subseries, 1991-1999 and undated
    Contains working files of On the Issues staff members, primarily editors and production assistants. Production assistant staff files include considerable subscriber correspondence. Files are organized by name, with the approximate job title or department shown in parentheses. On the Issues staff rosters are available for reference in the Reading Room's inventory files; please contact Research Services. See the Staff Files Subseries in the Choices Series for additional material on many of these staff members.
    - Aisenberg, Karen (Assistant Editor and subscriber correspondence), 1991-1992, 5 folders (Box OTI22)
    - Bray, Rosemary (Editor), hiring announcement, 1997 Jan. 1 (Box OTI22)
    - Greenberg, Mary Lou (Production Assistant/Managing Editor)
      - 1998, 2 folders (Box OTI22)
      - Billing and invoices, 1998 (Box OTI22)
    - Greenberg, Mary Lou (Production Assistant/Managing Editor) (Box OTI23)
      - Notebooks 1997-1998 and undated, 3 folders (Box OTI23)
      - Work updates 1997-1998, 2 folders (Box OTI23)
    - Kortright, Candide (Production Assistant and subscriber correspondence), 1996-1997 (Box OTI23)
    - Matthews, Donna (Executive Assistant)
      - 1998 and undated (Box OTI23)
      - Messages to return 1998-1999 (Box OTI23)
    - Menon, Kavita (Production Assistant), 1998 and undated (Box OTI23)
    - Reissman, Laura, work updates, 1998 (Box OTI23)
    - Rose, Karen (Production Editor and subscriber correspondence), 1995-1996, 1 of 3 folders (Box OTI23)
    - Rose, Karen (Production Editor and subscriber correspondence), 1995-1996, 2-3 of 3 folders (Box OTI24)
    - Ryder, Lee (Art Director), 1997-1998 (Box OTI24)
    - Sandroff, Ronnie (Editor), 1995-1996, 2 folders (Box OTI24)
    - Silver, Joy (Marketing)
      - Correspondence, 1995-1997 and undated (Box OTI24)
      - "To do for Joy," 1996 and undated (Box OTI24)
    - Sokol, Lori (Advertising Director), 1997 (Box OTI24)
    - Stoltenberg, John (Executive Editor), 1995-1996, 2 folders (Box OTI24)
  - Administration Subseries, 1987-2000 and undated
    Consists of personnel files, financial records, and other material related to the general administration of the magazine.
    - Administrative procedures notes, circa 1997 (Box OTI24)
    - Advertiser billing, 1997-1998 (Box OTI24)
    - Advertising, distribution, and direct mail statistics, 1994-1995 (Box OTI24)
    - Advertising rates, 1994 (Box OTI25)
    - Art design and printing contractors, 1987-1988 and undated (Box OTI25)
    - Back issue requests, 1996-1997 (Box OTI25)
    - Bindery invoices, 1996-1997 (Box OTI25)
    - Blank forms, undated (Box OTI25)
    - Brandeis complimentary subscriptions, 1998 (Box OTI25)
    - Budget planning, 1994 (Box OTI25)
    - Budgets, 1992-1994 (Box OTI25)
    - Check request forms and invoices, 1996-1998 (Box OTI25)
    - Direct mail list rentals - use of On the Issues list by others, 1995-2000, 2 folders (Box OTI25)
    - Editorial/production staff lists, 1997-1998 and undated (Box OTI25)
    - Editorial/production staff responsibilities, circa 1998 (Box OTI25)
    - Event planning - Solstice party, 1995, 1997, 2 folders (Box OTI25)
    - Financial analysis and job descriptions, 1991-1992 and undated (Box OTI25)
    - International Women's Issues database participation, 1995 (Box OTI25)
    - Internship programs, 1997 (Box OTI25)
    - Issue exchange list, 1995 and undated (Box OTI26)
    - Job descriptions, 1997 (Box OTI26)
    - Job descriptions, Editor and Editorial Director, 1996 and undated (Box OTI26)
    - Legal advice on establishing a private foundation, 1989 (Box OTI26)
    - Library of Congress ISSN forms, 1987 (Box OTI26)
    - Magazine management guides, 1983-1989 and undated (Box OTI26)
    - Managing editor hire, 1996 Aug. (Box OTI26)
    - On the Issues information sheets, circa 1996 (Box OTI26)
    - Post Office - second class permit application, 1992-1993 (Box OTI26)
    - Post Office - statement of ownership, 1993-1995 (Box OTI26)
    - Procedures meeting with Jan Goodwin, 1997 Nov. (Box OTI26)